{
    "topic": "Preamble",
    "Subject": "Indian Polity",
    "data": [
        {
            "question": "The Constitution of India borrowed the scheme of Indian Federation from the Constitution of",
            "op1": "Ireland",
            "op2": "UK",
            "op3": "anada",
            "op4": "USA",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following Constitutional System India follows ?",
            "op1": "US",
            "op2": "UK",
            "op3": "Switzerland",
            "op4": "Russia",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The inspiration of 'Liberty, Equality and Fraternity' was derived from",
            "op1": "merican revolution",
            "op2": "Russian revolution",
            "op3": "French revolution",
            "op4": "Italy revolution",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following describes India as a secular state ?",
            "op1": "Fundamental Rights",
            "op2": "Directive Principles of State Policy",
            "op3": "Fifth Schedule",
            "op4": "Preamble of the Constitution",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "In a parliamentary form of government, real powers of the State are vested in the",
            "op1": "President",
            "op2": "Chief Justice of Supreme Court",
            "op3": "ouncil of Ministers headed by the Prime Minister",
            "op4": "Parliament",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The Constitution of India has borrowed Fundamental duties from which one of the following countries ?",
            "op1": "Canada",
            "op2": "Erstwhile USSR",
            "op3": "UK",
            "op4": "Ireland",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement describes that the Indian Constitution is federal ?",
            "op1": "written and rigid Constitution",
            "op2": "An independent Judiciary",
            "op3": "Distribution of powers between the entre and States",
            "op4": "Vesting of residuary powers with the Centre",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the meaning of Secularism ?",
            "op1": "Freedom of worship to minorities",
            "op2": "Suppression of Religions",
            "op3": "A system of political and social philosophy that does not favour any particular religious faith",
            "op4": "Separation of Religion from State",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which among the following is true about Federal State ?",
            "op1": "Centre is more powerful than States",
            "op2": "States are more powerful than the Centre",
            "op3": "Equal powers for entre and States",
            "op4": "A Presidential form of government functions",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The source of India's sovereignty lies in the :",
            "op1": "President",
            "op2": "Prime Minister",
            "op3": "Directive Principles of State Policy",
            "op4": "Preamble to the Constitution",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The Preamble of the Indian Constitution was for the first time amended by the",
            "op1": "24th mendment",
            "op2": "42nd Amendment",
            "op3": "44th Amendment",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the following words in the Preamble of the Constitution of India, which was not inserted through the Constitution (Forty Second Amendment) Act, 1976 ?",
            "op1": "Socialist",
            "op2": "Secular",
            "op3": "Dignity",
            "op4": "Integrity",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following is not mentioned in the Preamble to the Constitution of India ?",
            "op1": "Justice",
            "op2": "Fraternity",
            "op3": "Adult franchise",
            "op4": "Equality of position",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The Preamble of our Constitution reads India as",
            "op1": "Socialist, Democratic, Secular Republic",
            "op2": "Democratic, Sovereign, Secular, Socialist Republic",
            "op3": "Sovereign, Democratic, Socialist, Secular Republic",
            "op4": "Sovereign, Socialist, Secular, emocratic Republic",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "Who proposed the Preamble before the drafting committee of the Constitution ?",
            "op1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "op2": ".R. Ambedkar",
            "op3": "B.N. Rao",
            "op4": "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "According to Preamble, the ultimate power lies in hands of:",
            "op1": "President",
            "op2": "Parliament",
            "op3": "People",
            "op4": "Constitution",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The Preamble of the Indian Constitution makes no mention of",
            "op1": "Fraternity",
            "op2": "Equality of status",
            "op3": "Justice",
            "op4": "Adult franchise",
            "answer:": 4
        }
    ]
}